<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Computers and Internet on A Developer&#39;s Experience</title>
    <link>/categories/computers-and-internet/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Computers and Internet on A Developer&#39;s Experience</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 May 2016 07:49:39 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/categories/computers-and-internet/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Text Editors</title>
      <link>/posts/text-editors-rundown/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2016 07:49:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/text-editors-rundown/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am not a *nix commands expert … but a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.johndcook.com/blog/2014/10/18/experts-vs-professionals/&#34;&gt;professional&lt;/a&gt;? So why not relish educating my brother a couple of nifty commands, especially – &lt;code&gt;find&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;grep&lt;/code&gt;, which he was looking into at the time. You can find a few more &lt;a href=&#34;/pages/cmd-line-quickies&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; if you are interested.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Written in Stone</title>
      <link>/pages/written-in-stone/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2015 06:58:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/pages/written-in-stone/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This article was &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/bits-bytes-stones-vivek-ragunathan&#34;&gt;published&lt;/a&gt; also on LinkedIn.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;academia&#34;&gt;Academia&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Mamallapuram Shore Temple, constructed on the deep southern shores of the Bay of Bengal, is one of the oldest stone structures on the planet. It was built around the beginning of the Anno Domini (AD). The site consists of three temple structures, subsidiary structures, and statues primarily built with granite. Prominent statues are that of a lion and elephant with great significance in the way it was rock-cut. Chariots are the primary subsidiary structures other than the temple. It is inevitable not to be marveled at the temple design, intricate and precise carvings and inscriptions. Carvings are made on a monolithic rock on which the works of an elephant and its ear with its loose skin are nearly impossible even today. Inscriptions, according to linguists, is poetic and metaphorical, a sophisticated language nevertheless. Another marvel is Krishna’s Butter Ball, a massive boulder of rock sitting tight above a rocky slope.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A funny moment of IoC</title>
      <link>/2015/07/08/a-funny-moment-of-ioc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2015 06:16:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/2015/07/08/a-funny-moment-of-ioc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Inversion_of_control&#34;&gt;IoC&lt;/a&gt; - Inversion of control, is a design that enables fluid flow of control by decoupling  tight dependencies between the portion of a code that exhibits behavior and  another portion of code that provides required functionality. One form of IoC, as we know, is Dependency Injection (DI). For instance, a &lt;code&gt;TextEditor&lt;/code&gt; could refer an &lt;code&gt;ISpellChecker&lt;/code&gt; instead of direct coupling to a specific implementation of spell checker thereby enabling the text editor to switch spell checker or even use more than one.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dealing with Bad Code</title>
      <link>/2013/02/11/dealing-with-bad-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2013 18:30:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/2013/02/11/dealing-with-bad-code/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Read this fine article by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.joelonsoftware.com/&#34;&gt;Joel Spolsky&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.joelonsoftware.com/articles/fog0000000069.html&#34;&gt;Things You Should Never Do&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is a great article, one that invokes mixed feelings. The article talks against rewriting (large scale) software…..from scratch. Joel was kind enough to consider all those who write software as true programmers; people who give enough thought and not just code up something that works. However, it is far different in the real world. That said, I am neither completely in disagreement with Joel nor am I advocating to rewrite large scale software once the code is identified as a mess.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>To Ritchie !!!</title>
      <link>/post/2011-10-17-toritchie/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2011 15:34:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2011-10-17-toritchie/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://cm.bell-labs.com/who/dmr/&#34;&gt;Dennis Ritchie&lt;/a&gt;, whom we all know as the creator of the C programming language passed away on Oct 12, 2011. We have lost one of the brilliant minds of mankind. I owe him this post for he has been one of the greatest inspirations in my life and the very reason that I am into programming.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Meeting Martin</title>
      <link>/post/2010-12-21-meeting-martin/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2010 13:32:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2010-12-21-meeting-martin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You may not know the guy in black. You should definitely be knowing the guy in green. &lt;a href=&#34;http://martinfowler.com/aboutMe.html&#34;&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t you&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The WD Anti-Propaganda Campaign !!!</title>
      <link>/2009/01/25/the-wd-anti-propaganda-campaign/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2009 22:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/2009/01/25/the-wd-anti-propaganda-campaign/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div style=&#34;font-family:Tahoma;&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Thanks to the internet. If nobody else bothers or understands what loss of data means, you can shout it aloud here. I lost 500GB of data &amp;#8211; every moment of my personal and professional life captured in bits and bytes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
