<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>windows phone on A Developer&#39;s Experience</title>
    <link>/tags/windows-phone/</link>
    <description>Recent content in windows phone on A Developer&#39;s Experience</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2013 03:48:57 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/windows-phone/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Windows Phone Epic !!!</title>
      <link>/2013/11/28/the-windows-phone-epic/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2013 03:48:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/11/28/the-windows-phone-epic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dear Reader,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do not be overwhelmed at the length of the article. I have tried my best to keep the length of the article not directly proportional to the time required to read it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oscar Wilde said, &lt;em&gt;If you want to tell people the truth, make them laugh, otherwise they’ll kill you&lt;/em&gt;. There are times when truth tends to be subjective, such as this article. However, I have definitely added the fun component to keep up earlier promise. Consider the time you spent reading this article as a break from your work or routine. I am sure you will enjoy it; doesn’t matter if you are using a Windows Phone 1. Perhaps you will read it again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am programmer[^2], gadget savvy, an avid fan of Microsoft products (especially Visual Studio and associated suite of development tools), and an honest critic of any product I use. I have an Android Phone, an iPhone, and for a few months now, a Windows Phone. And this is my experience with the Windows Phone – good, bad and grey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To begin with, the Windows Phone landscape (app and feature set) is dry and unpromising. There are a few good things here and there to console ourselves for the money we spent on the phone, and for the love of Microsoft!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
