<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Scala on A Developer&#39;s Experience</title>
    <link>/tags/scala/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Scala on A Developer&#39;s Experience</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/scala/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Declaring Implicits</title>
      <link>/posts/declaring-implicits/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/declaring-implicits/</guid>
      <description>While implicits are easy to use, declaring them properly requires careful consideration. Because there are a few different ways you can declare implicits viz. extension methods, parameter values, type converters and dynamic instances. Each one has a specific purpose. For instance, dynamic instances enable recursive implicit resolution. Understanding the different ways of declaring implicits is critical in choosing the right one for the given scenario. It is also invaluable in troubleshooting subtle bugs and unexpected behavior related to implicit resolution.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Scala Story</title>
      <link>/posts/my-scala-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/my-scala-story/</guid>
      <description>I have been reading the &lt;em&gt;My Scala Story&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://softwaremill.com/blog/?tag=myscalastory&#34;&gt;series&lt;/a&gt; by Software Mill - a short interview of renowned experts about their Scala journey. I have not done anything substantial in the OSS space to be on Software Mill&amp;rsquo;s radar. But their series inspired me to share mine. So, here it goes &amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optional Parameters</title>
      <link>/posts/optional-parameters/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/optional-parameters/</guid>
      <description>The billion dollar mistake has been committed already. No going back. But it is not necessary to keep repeating it. Oh, I am talking about the infamous &lt;code&gt;null&lt;/code&gt;. Would Java&amp;rsquo;s &lt;code&gt;Optional&lt;/code&gt; come to the rescue? Or are there any ironic &amp;ldquo;Don&amp;rsquo;ts&amp;rdquo; when using &lt;code&gt;Optional&lt;/code&gt;?</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
